V V SUNIL KUMAR MANYAM

Email: mvv.sunil@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-9008141141

Hands-on technical person with 11 years of experience in architecture, design, development, and implementation of complex software systems using Java/J2ee technologies with specialized knowledge in high data volumes with low latency and high throughput system, looking to continue making a significant contribution in architecture and design for unsolved problems.

<u>Professional Summary</u>

- Experienced in using the latest technologies in projects like Ehcache, Aerospike, MongoDB, Elasticsearch to achieve High data volumes and low latency and scalable applications.
- Experienced in building from scratch or decoupling the software modules to achieve the **microservice** module
- Designed horizontally scalable n tier distributed systems.
- Strong in core computers science areas like **Design**, **Architecture**, **Data Structures**, and **Algorithms**.
- Strong troubleshooting, **problem-solving** skills with result oriented approaches.
- Experienced in working in an Agile based team, played the role of the Scrum master for multiple projects.
- Excellent Inter-team communication to resolve ambiguous dependencies.
- Excellent Communication and customer interaction experience.

<u>Software Skill Summary</u>

- languages: Java, J2ee, Net C#, Adobe Flex, C, C++
- Framework/Patterns: Rabbitmq, Kafka, ehCache, Kinesis
- Database stores: MySQL, MongoDB, Aerospike, Elasticsearch
- Servers: Apache Tomcat
- Tools/Packages: Maven, SVN, Eclipse, IntelliJ
- Operating System: Windows, Centos, Ubuntu, RHEL5, iOS
- Miscellaneous: Oops designing skills, Data structures, and Algorithms

Work Experience

BIL Pricing (June, 2018 to Present)

Amazon, Hyderabad

BIL is the tool which helps the Amazon international seller to list the products from source market place to other (cross region) target market places. Pricing plays a key vital role in BIL as there is a need for re-pricing the products in target market places based on the factors like shipping price difference, VAT, currency fluctuations, etc..

Designing, building and enhancing the technology stack for the new pricing rule in BIL which supports pricing for European sellers. Also played a key role in re-architecting the BIL tool to separate the pricing components for better granularity(microservice architecture), better reusability, and maintainability. Also played scrum master role for this project.

<u>Technologies Used</u>: Java, Kinesis, SOAP, MongoDB.

Checkers Project

(April, 2017 to May 2018)

Amazon, Hyderabad

Checkers is a key project for Amazon in terms of providing a better experience for China-based sellers by getting there funds directly disbursed to there bank accounts, instead of via third-party tool called Payoneer. This project not only helps the Chinese seller to get a better experience but also helps Amazon in saving the committon paid to third-party customers.

Played a key role in enhancing existing registration flow and settings page and delivering the product to provide support for Checkers in place of existing third-party tool Payoneer for China based sellers. As I am the only individual technical contributor(worked as a loaner) for this project interacted with multiple cross region teams like Registration, Settings page, Product management, China legal team and also the Higher management team to get correct traction for this project.

Technologies Used: Java, Javascript, REST, G2S2(ion).

Achievement: "Above and Beyond" Award for this project.

<u>Buyer Seller Message Feature</u> <u>Snapdeal , Bangalore</u>

(December, 2015 to March 2017)

BuyerSeller message feature aids in building a loyal customer database, reduce the CPS (contacts per suborder) and control product returns. Sellers can use this chat facility to interact with buyers who initiate a conversation with them. This way if consumers are unhappy with their purchases they can talk to the seller directly. Sellers can also be allowed to contact buyers freely in order to avoid RTO (courier return).

Played a key role in building technology stack and important modules in the project like offers flow and cache module, also responsible for communicating with dependent teams to resolving issues and push the feature on time. Responsible for mentoring the junior members of the team.

Technologies Used: Java, AeroSpike, REST, SQL.

Achievement: Received **Spot Award** for this project.

(June, 2016 to March 2017)

Seller Front Mobile API's

<u>Snapdeal , Bangalore</u>

Seller Front Mobile API's team provides the data to Android and IOS teams through REST endpoints. SF Mobile API's team gets data from different teams in different ways with different standards and consolidate data to provide to Android and IOS in the required format.

Played a key role in enhancing product performance and decreasing the REST endpoints latency using technologies like caching and parallel programming. Supported the team with production support, code review and mentoring the junior members. Point of contact for the project for external components.

<u>Technologies Used</u>: Java, Spring MVC, SQL, EhCache, Aerospike

Seller Rating Panel (SRP)

(April, 2015 to February, 2016)

Snapdeal, Bangalore

Seller rating panel is part of the seller front in seller.snapdeal.com web. It is a platform for all the Sellers of Snapdeal to see their active ratings and historical trends. It also provides high-level details about how his rating is calculated with customer comments and feedbacks, so that can improve their ratings. SRP also provides the impersonate view for account managers to see all seller information.

Developed most of the components in the product from UI to DB. Developed and showcase the new features to Seller onboarding team and higher management for best customer experience. Improved the response time of the REST endpoints using Ehcache.

Technologies Used: Java, Spring MVC, REST, SQL, EhCache

Achievement: Received **Spot Award** for this project.

Watch4Net/ProSphere

(January, 2011 to March, 2015)

EMC2, Bangalore

Watch4Net or Prosphere suite is enterprise-class crossdomain performance and service level management software. Perform crossdomain performance monitoring of infrastructure and data center components, in realtime, to a single customizable dashboard.

Developed the new Alert consolidation flows for VNX, VMware, VMax alert consolidation and enhanced the existing data consolidations. Developed RESTFul service for maintaining the configuration of the product. Played a vital role in fixing the customer escalation for the product and enhancing the monitoring tool in the product.

Technologies Used: Java, Spring, Oracle PL/SQL, Rabbitmq.

<u>Achievement</u>: One of the very few people to get **Gold Award** for developing the **Mobile App** POC for the product this project (**stretch activity**)

<u>Left Hand Networks</u> <u>HPSTSD Bangalore</u>

LeftHand Networks provides server virtualization that converts the DAS into ISCSI SAN. This product makes use of the unused space on hypervisors like ESX servers to create a clustered ISCSI SAN. The virtual clustered ISCSI SAN has features like Network Raid, Replication, Snapshot, etc..

Responsible for the Developing the Client side product 02VSA which enables the deployment of LHN cluster on ESX server from scratch. Involved in writing and testing the JUNIT's for the core functionality in of LHN to integrate them with a unified infrastructure platform. Involved addition of other new feature as well as unittesting.

Technologies Used: Java 1.5, .NET C#, C++

WAI(Windows Adaptive Infrastructure) HPSTSD, Bangalore

(July, 2008 to February, 2010)

Windows Adaptive Infrastructure is a NAS Cluster which provides Scalable File Serving and application high availability through virtualization. The product enables multiple SQL Server instances to be consolidated onto substantially fewer servers.

Played a significant role in porting the product filesystem to WIN2K8 server which also involved fixing the issues in the core component of the product, rootcausing and resolving some of the critical HA(High Availability) defects. Developed the test tools which help to reduce the QA cycle and improve the quality of the product.

Technologies Used: C++, .Net C#

Education Summary

Bachelor of Technology in Computer		Vellore Institute of Technology (Deemed	
Science Engineering	2008	University), Vellore	75%
Class XII (Board of Intermediate			
Education)	2004	SASI Junior College, Vellivennu	86.2%
Class X (Board of Secondary Education	n) 2002	SASI Junior College, Vellivennu	77.5%